Guide to the Institute for the Future Reports M1186
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Institute for the Future: reports
1969-2015
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Institute for the Future
M1186
25.5 Linear Feet: (47 boxes, 1 oversize folder)
Forecasting reports published by the Institute for the Future.
Scope and Contents
Materials consist of reports, special reports, papers, working papers, and correspondence. The documents include IFTF issued reports, announcements, newsletters, etc., IFTF research commissioned through government grants or contracts, and IFTF research commissioned by private companies or organizations.
Biographical / Historical
The Institute for the Future (IFTF) is a non-profit strategic futures organization located in Palo Alto, California. The IFTF was founded in 1968 by a group of former RAND Corporation researchers with a grant from the Ford Foundation.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use. Most reports (those in the Accession 2017-188) have been scanned and are available digitally from https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4083255. Digital copies of Special Reports are embargoed for 75 years and are not available online. Special reports are available for viewing in the Reading Room, however, but they may not be reproduced.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Roy Amara, 1986, and Robert Johansen, 2001. Accessions 1986-057, 1987-038, 2001-015. Gift of Institute for the Future, 2017. Accession 2017-188.
Business forecasting; Economic forecasting -- United States.; Institute for the Future
- Accessions 1986-057, 1987-038, 2001-015 (Boxes 1 - 12)
  - Lipinski, Hubert and Robert P. Plummer. Graphic Communication in a Group Setting, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The HUB Communication System, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Teletext and Videotex: Publications, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Technological Trends in the U.S. Television Industry: The Next Five Years, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Nyhan, Michael J. A National League of Cities/OPRE: Teleconference on Human Services Planning, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Amara, Roy. Planning for Arizona's Future, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Amara, Roy. Toward the Year 2000: National Priorities, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Johansen, Robert and Robert DeGrasse. Computer- Based Teleconferencing: Effects on Working Patterns, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Johansen, Robert. The Common Sense of Trying Out Videotex, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Use of Dycim in Forecasting, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - National Defense University. Crop Yields and Climate Change to the Year 2000, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - National Defense University. Climate Change to the Year 2000, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - National Networking among UAPs: Interim Report, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - CAP (Corporate Associate Program for a Long-Term Perspective) Report, 1981-83 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - McNeal, Barbara and Robert Johansen. Electronic Education with Reduced Expectations: A Report on Teleconferencing, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Tydeman, John, Ian Morrison, Draginja Kasap and Mary Poulin. The Cost of Laboratory Technology: A Framework for Cost Management, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Tydeman, John, J. Ian Morrison, Paul A. Cassidy, David F. Hardwick and William H. Chase. Analyzing the Factors Contributing to Rising Laboratory Costs, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Lipinski, Hubert and Richard P. Adler. The HUB Project, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Tydeman, John. Teletext and Videotex: Tomorrow's Technology Today, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Chupack, Stephen F., Edward Sbardellati, Karen Thomas, Lee Viets and Gail Wickes. User Perspectives: Vermonters Talk About a Telecommunications Demonstration, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Adler, Richard P. and Hubert M. Lipinski. HUB: A Computer-Based Communication System to Support Group Problem Solving, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Todd, Seldon P., Jr. and Michael T. Greelis. National Networking: A Case Study, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Zwimpfer, Laurence. The Chip at Work: Emerging Home Information Services, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Johansen, Robert, Kathleen J. Hansell and David Green. Growth in Teleconferencing; Looking Beyond the Rhetoric of Readiness, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Soviet Union to the Year 2000: International Economic Opportunities (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Spang, Sara, Barbara McNeal and Kathleen Spangler Vian. Interactive Group Modeling: Part 4: Some Preliminary Tests of the HUB System, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Lipinski, Hubert, Robert Plummer and Kathleen Spangler Vian. Interactive Group Modeling: Part 1: Extending Group Communication through Computers, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Vian, Kathleen Spangler, Hubert Lipinski, Robert Plummer and and Sara Spang. Interactive Group Modeling: Part 2: An Interactive Monitor, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - The HUB User Guide, Version 3, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Wilson, Thad and Hubert Lipinski. Internal Technical Memorandum No. 81: Monitor Statistics for the First Year of Planet-1 Operation, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Telecommunications and Service to the Developmentally Disabled, Volume 3: Decisions on Demonstration Projects [Alternate Media Center, New York University], 1979 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Technology Assessment of Teletext and Videotex in the United States: Standards Policy Workshop Background Papers, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Telecommunications and Service to the Developmentally Disabled, Volume 2: Application Possibilities [Alternate Media Center, New York University], 1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Amara, Roy. Key Issues for the Print Industry in the 80s, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Scenes from Possible Futures: New Information Systems and the Conduct of R&D, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Lipinski, Hubert and John Tydeman. Cross-Impact Analysis - Extended KSIM, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Changing Nature of Participation: Impact on the Corporation, Part II: Scenarios for the 1980s (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Schmid, Gregory. Productivity Failure? Reindustrialization? Careful!, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Amara, Roy. Strategic Planning in a Changing Corporate Environment, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Plummer, Robert P., Robert Johansen, Michael J. Nyhan and P.G. Holmlov. 4004 Futures for Teletext and Videotex in the U.S. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Spangler, Kathleen, Hubert Lipinski and Robert Plummer. Interactive Monitoring of Computer-Based Group Communication, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Amara, Roy. The Future of Voluntarisn: Meeting Changing Societal Needs, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Spangler Vian, Kathleen, Hubert Lipinski, Sara Spang and John Tydeman. Interactive Group Modeling: Part 3: HUB and the Modeling Process, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Amara, Roy and Gregory Schmid. The New Activism and the Corporation, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - The HUB User Guide, VersIon 3, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Randolph, Robert. Social and Technological Forecasting in the Soviet Union [Futures Magazine], 1976 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Vallee, Jacques and Thaddeus Wilson. Computer-Based Communication in Support of Scientific and Technical Work, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Tydeman, John and Laurence Zwimpfer. Videotex in the United States - Toward Information Diversity, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Amara, Roy. The Future of Management: Ten Shapers of Management in the 80s, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Vallee, Jacques and Thaddeus Wilson. Computer- Based Communication in Support of Scientific and Technical Work, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Johansen, Robert. Developing New Communications Media: Can We Account for the Human Dimensions?, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Amara, Roy. Imperatives for Tomorrow: The I's Have It: Images, Institutions, Involvement, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Helmer, Olaf, Theodore J. Gordon, Selwyn Enzer, Raul de Brigard and Richard Rochberg. Development of Long-Range Forecasting Methods for Connecticut: A Summary, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Salanick, Gerald R., Theodore J. Gordon and Neale Adams. On the Nature of Economic Losses Arising from Computer-Based Systems in the Next Fifteen Years, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Johansen, Robert and Patricia A. Samuel. The Pragmatics of Long-Range Planning, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Community Teleconferencing Centers: Phase I Report, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Forecasting the Market for Teleconferencing: An Interim Report, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Teleconference on Integrated Data Bases in Postsecondary Education: A Transcript and Summary, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Nyhan, Michael J. The Videotex Invention: Marvel or Myth?, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Lipinski, Hubert, Sara Spang and John Tydeman. Supporting Task-Focused Communication, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Johansen, Robert, Barbara McNeal and Michael Nyhan. Telecommunications and Developmentally Disabled People: Evaluations of Audio Conferencing, Personal Computers, Computer Conferencing, Electronic Mail, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Johnson, D. Gale. The World Grain Economy and Climate Change to the Year 2000: Implications for Policy [National Defense University], 1983 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Impact of Diagnostic Technologies on the Practice of Medicine, 1982-95, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Marshall, Thomas H. Information Terminals [Stanford Research Institute], 1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Enzer, Selwyn. A Case Study Using Forecasting as a Decisionmaking Aid, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Adler, Richard P., Michael J. Nyhan and John Tydeman. Electronic Yellow Pages and the Forefront of U.S. Videotex Policy Debate, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Tydeman, John, J. Ian Morrison, David F. Hardwick and Paul A. Cassidy. The Cost of Quality Control Procedures in the Clinical Laboratory, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - New Strategies for Innovations in Medical Information Systems, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Connell, Eileen. Establishing a Telephone Conferencing System: The Dynamics of Doing It [Alternate Media Center, New York University], 1980 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Lipinski, Hubert and Sara Spang. Communication in Interactive Simulation, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Tydeman, John. Forecasting a New Hybrid Technology - Teletext and Videotex, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Tydeman, John, Hubert Lipinski and Sara Spang. An Interactive Computer-Based Approach to Aid Group Problem Formulation, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Choosing an Electronic Message System: A Guide for the Human Services, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 1982-83 Videotex Directory: A Guide to the Videotex/Teletext Industries [Arlen Communications Inc.] (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Spangler Vian, Kathleen, Hubert Lipinski, Robert Plummer and Sara Spang. Interactive Group Modeling: Part 2: An Interactive Monitor, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Testing and Evaluating a Teleconference Model as a Management Tool in the Planning Process, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Heler, Olaf. On the Future State of the Union, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Baran, Paul. Potential Market Demand for Two-Way Information Services to the Home, 1970-1990, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Gordon, Theodore J., Richard Rochberg and Selwyn Enzer. Research on Cross-Impact Techniques with Applications to Selected Problems in Economics, Political Science, and Technology Assessment, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Vallee, Jacque and Thaddeus Wilson. Computer-Based Communication in Support on Scientific and Technical Work, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Vallee, Jacques, Gerald Askevold and Thaddeus Wilson. Computer Conferencing in the Geosciences, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Vallee, Jacques, Hubert M. Lipinski and Richard H. Miller. Group Communication through Computers: Volume 1: Design and Use of the FORUM System, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Vallee, Jacques, Robert Johansen, Robert H. Hastings and Arthur C. Hastings. Group Communication through Computers: Volume 2: A Study of Social Effects, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Vallee, Jacques, Robert Johansen, Hubert Lipinski, Kathleen Spangler, Thaddeus Wilson and Andrew Hardy. Group Communication through Computers: Volume 3: Pragmatics and Dynamics, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Vallee, Jacques, Robert Johansen, Hubert Lipinski, Kathleen Spangler and Thaddeus Wilson. Group Communication through Computers: Volume 4: Social, Managerial and Economics Issues, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Johansen, Robert, Robert DeGrasse, Jr. and Thaddeus Wilson. Group Communication through Computers: Volume 5: Effects on Working Patterns, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Schmid, G. and A. Lipinski. Workshop Proceedings: Noneconomic Factors in Energy Supply and Demand [Electric Power Research Institute], 1980 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - CAP Report; Teleconferencing IFTF Client Services brochure, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Baran, Paul and Andrew J. Lipinski. The Future of the Telephone Industry, 1970-1985, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Enzer, Selwyn. Some Developments in Plastics and Competing Materials by 1985, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Nagelberg, Mark and Dennis L. Little. Selected Urban Simulations & Games, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Nagelberg, Mark. Simulation of Urban Systems - A Selected Bibliography, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Baran, Paul. Japanese Competition in the Information Industry, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - The Future of the Corporation in an Increasingly Participating Society, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Gordon, Theodore J. and Robert H. Ament. Forecasts of Some Technological and Scientific Developments and Their Societal Consequences, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Helmer, Olaf and Helen Helmer. Future Opportunities for Foundation Support, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Amara, Roy. Toward a Framework for National Goals and Policy Research, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Amara, Roy. The Social Responsibilities of Business, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Enzer, Selwyn. Cross-Impact Techniques in Technology Assessment, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Lipinski, Andrew J., Hubert M. Lipinski and Robert H. Randolph. Computer-Assisted Expert Interrogation: A Report on Current Methods Development, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Amara, Roy. The Futures Field: Fuctions, Forms, and Critical Issues [Futures Magazine], 1974 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Lipinski, H. M. and R. H. Miller. FORUM: A Computer-Assisted Communications Medium (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Johansen, Robert, Richard H. Miller and Jacques Vallee. Group Communication through Electronic Media: Fundamental Choices and Social Effects [Educational Technology Magazine], 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Vallee, Jacques and Gerald Askevold. Information Organization for Interactive Use: Design Implications in Data-Base Systems [Journal of the American Society for Information Science], 1973 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Johansen, Robert and John A. Ferguson. Mapping Views of the Future in a Small Group [Futures Magazine], 1976 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Johansen, Robert. Pitfalls in the Social Evaluation of Teleconferencing Media [University of Wisconsin], 1976 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Amara, Roy and Jacques Vallee. FORUM: A Computer-Based System to Support Interaction among People, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Vallee, Jacques. The FORUM Project: Network Conferencing and Its Future Applications [Computer Networks Magazine], 1976 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Johansen, Robert, Jacques Vallee and Michael Palmer. Computer Conferencing: Measurable Effects on Working Patterns, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Vallee, Jacques and Thaddeus Wilson. Computer Networks and the Interactive Use of Geologic Data: Recent Experiments in Teleconferencing, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Schmid, Gregory. Interdependence Has Its Limits [Foreign Policy Magazine], 1975 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Amara, Roy. Some Observations on the Interaction of Technology and Society [Futures Magazine] (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Vallee, Jacques. There Ain't No User Science: A Tongue-in-Cheek Discussion of Interactive Systems, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Johansen, Robert, Jacques Vallee and Kent Collins. Learning the Limits of Teleconferencing: Design of a Teleconferencing Tutorial, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Lipinski, Andrew and Denis Loveridge. How We Forecast: Institute for the Future's Study of the UK, 1978-95 [Futures Magazine], 1982 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Amara, Roy. Looking Ahead to the Third Century [World Magazine], 1976 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Amara, Roy and Andrew J. Lipinski. Linking the Corporation to the Future, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Amara, Roy. Planning, Futures, and the Skeptics, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Vallee, Jacques. Modeling as a Communication Process: Computer Conferencing Offers New Perspectives [Technological Forecasting and Social Change Magazine], 1977 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Johansen, Robert and Patricia Samuel. Futurology Applied to Education: Some Basic Elements, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Amara, Roy. Five Emergent Features of U.S. Society and Their Impact on Management in the Next Decade, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Johansen, Robert. Social Evaluations of Teleconferencing: A Summary [Telecommunications Policy Journal], 1977 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Johansen, Robert. Interpersonal Communication through Computers: An Introduction to Computer Mail and Computer Conferencing, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Johansen, Robert, Jacques Vallee and Kathleen Spangler. Electronic Meetings: Utopian Dreams and Complex Realities [The Futurist Magazine], 1978 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Lipinski, Hubert, Roy Amara and Kathleen Spangler. Communication Needs in Computer Modeling, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Baran, Paul. Computer-Communications for the Community Information Utility (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - McNeal, Barbara and Robert Johansen. Electronic Education with Reduced Expectations: A Report on Teleconferencing, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Ament, Robert H. Comparison of Delphi Forecasting Studies in 1964 and 1969 [Futures Magazine] (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Vallee, Jacques. Network Conferencing. [Datamation Magazine], 1974 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Amara, Roy and Andrew Lipinski. Strategic Planning: Penetrating the Corporate Barriers, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Vallee, Jacques, Robert Johansen, Hubert Lipinski and Thaddeus Wilson. Pragmatics and Dynamics of Computer Conferencing: A Summary of Findings from the FORUM Project, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Johansen, Robert and Jacques Vallee. Impact of a Computer-Based Communications Network on the Working Patterns of Researchers, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Vallee, Jacques and Bradford Gibbs. Distributed Management of Scientific Projects: An Analysis of Two Computer-Conferencing Experiments at NASA, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Strategic Planning Services: The Corporation's Link to the Future [brochure for prospective clients] (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Telecommunications and Computing: Typical Projects Corporate Strategic Model Development [leaflets] (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Nyhan, Michael J., Robert Johansen and Robert Plummer. Home Information Systems: Some Thoughts on the Role of Public Broadcasting, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Institute for the Future Newsletter: 1979, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - CAP Report: 1979-1983 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Enzer, Selwyn and Raul de Brigard. Issues and Opportunities in the State of Connecticut: 1970-2000 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Helmer, Olaf and Helen Helmer. Future Opportunities for Foundation Support, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Enzer, Selwyn, Dennis Little and Frederick D. Lazar. Some Prospects for Social Change by 1985 and Their Impact on Time/Money Budgets, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - de Brigard, Raul and Olaf Helmer. Some Potential Societal Developments: 1970-2000 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Enzer, Selwyn, Theodore J. Gordon, Richard Rochberg and Robert Buchele. A Simulation Game for the Study of State Policies, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Institute for the Future informational brochures (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Electronic Information Services, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Medical Equipment and Supplies, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Telecommunications Equipment, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Telecommunications Networks, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Computers, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Consumer Electronics, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Drugs and Pharmaceuticals, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Electronic Components, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Electronic Information Services, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Technology Horizons: The Next 20 Years, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - 2000 Ten-Year Forecast (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Health and Health Care 2010: The Forecast, the Challenge, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - The decade ahead; a report from the Institute for the Future, relative inflation rates, 1979-1990 in The Washington Post Magazine, Feb. 15, 1981 (Map-folder 12)
- Accession 2017-188 (Boxes 13-48)
  - Political Analysis of the Future (APSA)/ O. Helmer, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Non-Proliferation Treaty at the Crossroads/ A. Kramish, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - On the Impact of the New Communications Media upon Social Values/ P. Baran, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Some Possible Futures of American Religion/ T. Gordon, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Some Commercial and Industrial Aspects of the Space Program/ S. Enzer, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - "Potential Institutional Arrangements of Organizations Involved in the Exploitation of Remotely Sensed Earth Resources Data/ T. Gordon S. Enzer", 1970 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Long-Range Forecasting—Roles and Methods/ O. Helmer, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Information Theory, Cross-Impact Matrices, and Pivotal Events/ R. Rochberg, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Comparison of Delphi Forecasting Studies in 1964 and 1969/ R. Ament, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - On the State-of-the-Art of Computer Development by the Year 2000/ P. Baran, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - 1969 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Current Methods of Futures Research/ T. Gordon, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - "Construction of Delphi Statements/ J. Salancik W. Wenger E. Helfer", 1972 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - "Forecasting/ R. Amara J. Salancik", 1972 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Cross-Impact Techniques in Technology Assessment/ S. Enzer, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Social Responsibility of Business/ R. Amara, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Japanese Competition in the Information Industry/ P. Baran, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Framework for National Science Policy Analyses/ R. Amara, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - "Some Views on the Use of Expert Judgment/ R. Amara A. Lipinski", 1972 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Toward a Framework for National Goals and Policy Research/ R. Amara, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Computer-Communications for the Community Information Utility/ P. Baran, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Note on Cross-impact Analysis/ R. Amara, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Social Indicators, Policy Analysis and Simulation/ D. Little, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - "Computer-Assisted Expert Interrogation/ A. Lipinski H. Lipinski R. Randolph", 1972 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Futures Field/ R. Amara, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - "FORUM/ H. Lipinski R. Miller", 1974 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - "Group Communication through Electronic Media/ R. Johansen R. Miller J. Vallee", 1974 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Network Conferencing/ J. Vallee, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - "Information Organization for Interactive Use/ J. Vallee G. Askevold", 1973 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - "Strategic Planning/ R. Amara A. Lipinski", 1974 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Assessing a Problem-Oriented Social Technology/ S. Enzer, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Next 25 Years/ R. Amara, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Dynamics of Long-Term Growth/ F. Meyer, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - "Computer Conference/ J. Vallee R. Johansen K. Spangler", 1975 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - "Geologic Application of Network Conferencing/ J. Vallee G. Askevold", 1975 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - "Mapping Views of the Future in a Small Group/ R. Johansen J. Ferguson", 1976 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Investment Opportunities in Food Production in LDCs/ G. Schmid, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 37)